Carpenter, Jesse Records 5490
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Jesse Carpenter Records
1912-1966
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Carpenter, Jesse
5490
4 cubic feet
4 linear ft.
Correspondence, collective labor agreements, papers (documents).
Handwritten notes, agendas, correspondence, address books, contracts, miscellaneous notes, sound discs
5657050
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
M. Clark, November 20, 2015
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 14, 2019
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5192: Paul Abelson Papers
Carpenter, Jesse; International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Stablemen, and Helpers of America; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America; United States. Federal Trade Commission
5657050
- International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs: Article VII; Article XII; Article IV; Article IX; Article 7 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Administrative Problems (handwritten notes) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Appointment Calendar from 1948 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Confederated Unions of America (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Cooperating Agencies (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Preliminaries: Union (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Cooperative Area vs. Industry-wide Bargaining (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Agenda pages (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Communications (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Calendar pages w/notes (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Piece rates (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Initial Differences (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Handbook notes - work standards; Disputes; Executive Director; Company Admin., etc. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- District of Columbia - Info.: Florida - Info.; Georgia - Info.; Idaho; Ill. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Indiana - Information; Indianapolis; Iowa; Kansas; Kentucky; Louisiana; Maine; Maryland; Mass.; Boston; Mich. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- New Hampshire; New Jersey; New Mexico; Nevada - Information (Box 1, Folder 16)
- North Carolina; North Dakota; New York City (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Oklahoma & Oregon - Information (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Ohio - notes and information (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Pennsylvania notes and information (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Rhode Island; Tennessee; Texas; Utah; Vermont; Virginia; Washington - Information (Box 1, Folder 21)
- West Virginia; Wisconsin; Wyoming - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 22)
- SLRB Unfair Labor Practice (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Companies - - A-B (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Companies - - C-D (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Companies - - E-F (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Companies - - G-H (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Companies - - I-L (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Companies - - M-N (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Companies - - O-R (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Companies - - S-T (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Companies - - U-Z (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Prof. Jesse Carpenter - name tag (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Alabama; Arizona; Arkansas; California; Detroit; Colorado; Connecticut; Delaware; Los Angeles - Company information (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Minnesota; Duluth; Minneapolis; St. Paul; Mississippi; Missouri; Montana; Nebraska; Nevada; Sacramento; San Francisco - Company information (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Hand written notes about companies (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Company addresses (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Address and Telephone Books (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Notes (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Industry listing (Box 2, Folder 9)
- NYSSILR - Employes Assoc. and Collective Bargaining in New York City - part II, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- NYSSILR - Employes Assoc. and Collective Bargaining in New York City - part II, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Correspondence and questionnaires (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Union Contract File A (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Union Contract B (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Union Contract C (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Union Contract D-E (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Company Information - No particular order - hand written notes (Box 2, Folder 17)
- "III" - Notes on Furriers, 1927-1932 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- "III" - Enforcement by Court (Box 2, Folder 19)
- "IV" - Cap makers, 1927-1937 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- "VII" - Titles of clippings generally - most are of like value (Box 2, Folder 21)
- "VIII" - Notes on Millinery, 1933-1936 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- "XI" - Notes about Furriers, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- "XIII" - Furrier's Strikes, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Employer Group - Notes on Employer (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Miscellaneous Union Notes, 1925-1936 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Miscellaneous Company Notes (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Miscellaneous Notes (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Miscellaneous Company Notes - C-M: not in any particular order (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Notes annotated by day and time (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Notes - annotate by day and time (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Notes - annotated by day and time, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Presentation notes and presentation cards (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Miscellaneous Union notes (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Company notes - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 35)
- New York Background For Employers' Association (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Employers' Association and Collective Bargaining in New York (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Cornell University Examination Booklet - and 4 sound discs (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Hearing held this 11th day of May, 1944, at the War Labor Board at 220 East 42nd Street, New York City (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Notes and Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Clothing Accessories (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Motion Picture Operators Arguments (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Cloaks (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Material on Children's Dress, Bath Robes & House Dress Makers (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Women's Cloaks, Suits, Dresses & Waist, 1913-1918 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Fur Dressers & Dyers, 1915-1942 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Leather, 1935-1936 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Bakers, 1928-1929 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- ACWA: Clothing Workers & Chicago (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Fur Mfg. Ind., 1933-1934 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Fur Mfg. Ind., 1923-1924 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Fur Mfg. Ind., 1932 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Abelson's Decisions (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Competition and Collective Bargaining in the Needle Trades (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Policy of Countervailing Power (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Antitrust, Collective Bargaining and the Garment Industry: An Epilogue to Pennington and Jewel Tea, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Affidavits and Memorandum of Law (Box 3, Folder 19)
- United States of America Before Federal Trade Commission - Docket No. 4597 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Grand Jury Indictment - March 11, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- United States of America Before Federal Trade Commission - Docket No. 5088 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Milk Drivers Local 584, Int'l. Bro. of Teamsters and Sunydale Farms, Inc. Et al. (Box 3, Folder 23)
- United States District Court, Southern District of New York Criminal Action No. 158-181: Affidavit (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Exhibit A: Agreement dated January 2, 1950 - - Nat'l. Assoc. of Blouse Man., Inc. and Greater Blouse, Skirt and Neckware Contractors Assoc., Inc. (Box 3, Folder 25)
- United States of America v Greater Blouse, Skirt (Box 3, Folder 26)
- p. 16 of a manuscript - "multiple-employer bargaining" (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Grand Jury Indictment - March 11, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- State's Blouse Makers Oppose Bid to Toss Out Price-Fix Indictment, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- United States of America Before federal Trade Commission - Docket No. 3491 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Federal Trade Commission, Washington - May 26, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Federal Trade Commission, Washington: Sept. 23, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Some Central Ideas From Abeleson's Lectures at Cornell University in the Spring of 1949 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Partial Manuscripts (2 partial manuscripts with notes) (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Administration and Enforcement of Employer-Group Contracts: Chapter VII, VIII, IX (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Group Bargaining and Trade Practices: Chapter XIV (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Misc. Manuscript Pages (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Document: (Carpenter) Union Participation in Management's Rule Making Power (Box 3, Folder 38)
- History of Arbitration Before 1910 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Hospital Conference - Oct. 23-Nov. 3, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Enforcement of Standards: Chapter IX -- sound discs (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Sound Discs (Untitled) (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Does the Dress Industry Face a New Crisis or a Revival; Mud Slinging and Unethical Tactics in the Jewish Labor Movement (manuscripts and sound disc) (Box 3, Folder 43)
- 'Messenger in the Dress Trade Nulify'; 'What's Happening to the ILGWU'; 'Decision by the Impartial Chairman of the Dressmakers' [manuscripts and 1 sound disc] (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Cloak Industry: plus 1 sound disc (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Dressmakers plus 1 sound disc (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Dress Industry plus 1 sound disc (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Cap Manufacturing plus 1 sound disc (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Milinary plus 1 sound disc (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Pattern of Garments by Gus Tyler (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Conditions in the Women's Garment Industry (Box 3, Folder 51)
- A Brief History of Voluntary Arbitration Previous to 1910 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Union Participation in Management's Rule-Making Power (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Multiple Employe Bargaining (Box 3, Folder 54)
- Multiple Employer Bargaining (Box 3, Folder 55)
- Multiple Employer Bargaining (Box 3, Folder 56)
- Some Aspects of Employer-Group Bargaining with Labor Unions in New York City (Box 3, Folder 57)
- Competition and Collective Bargaining: Origin of the Protocol of Peace (Box 3, Folder 58)
- Protocol of Peace (Box 3, Folder 59)
- Multiple-Employer Bargaining and Business Competition in New York City (Box 3, Folder 60)
- Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Leather (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Cloak and Suit Mfg. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Leather: Contract Terms: Abelson's Decision (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Fur Dressing (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Dolls (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Bakers (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Cloak, Suit and Skirt Mfg. (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Cloaks (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Cloaks (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Hosiery (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Men's Clothing (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Fur (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Men: Rochester (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Hats (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Hats (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Men (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Men (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Dress: Contract Clauses (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Dress (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Millinery (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Fur Workers Contracts (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Fur Mfg. Industry, 1912-1919 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Miscellaneous Toy Mfg. 1950, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Hats (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Miscellaneous - Union agreements (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Fur Mfg. Industry, 1941-1945 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Fur Mfg. Industry, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Fur Mfg. Industry, 1938-1939 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Millinery, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Millinery, 1931-1932 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Women's Dress, 1947-1961 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Textile - Knitwear (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Pocketbooks (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Children's Wear (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Construction (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Fur (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Fur (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Men's Clothing (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Dress (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 42)